He's dying to become a chef.
Ratatouille is a animation, comedy, family film directed by Brad Bird.
Remy, a resident of Paris, has quite a sophisticated palate.
He would love to become a chef so he can create and enjoy
culinary masterpieces to his heart's delight.
The only problem is, Remy is a rat.
When he winds up in the sewer beneath one of Paris' finest restaurants,
Remy finds himself ideally placed to realize his dream.
He forms an unusual alliance with the restaurants rookie employee, and together they work through challenges stemming from Head Chef
Skinner, Remy’s colony, and renowned food critic Anton Ego, who strikes fear in the hearts of chefs all throughout France.
Remy (voice), played by Patton Oswalt.
Skinner (voice), played by Ian Holm.
Linguini (voice), played by Lou Romano.
Django (voice), played by Brian Dennehy.
Emile (voice), played by Peter Sohn.
Anton Ego (voice), played by Peter O'Toole.
Ratatouille ( RAT-ə-TOO-ee) is a 2007 American animated comedy-drama film written and
directed by Brad Bird, from a story by Jan Pinkava, Jim Capobianco and Bird.
Produced by Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures, the film stars the voices of Patton Oswalt, Lou
Romano, Ian Holm, Janeane Garofalo, Peter O'Toole, Brian Dennehy, Peter Sohn and Brad Garrett.
The title refers to the French dish ratatouille, and also
references the species of the main character, a rat.
Set mostly in Paris, the plot follows a young rat Remy (Oswalt) who dreams of becoming a chef at Auguste Gusteau's (Garrett) restaurant
and tries to achieve his goal by forming an unlikely alliance with the restaurant's garbage boy Alfredo Linguini (Romano).
Development for Ratatouille began in 2000 when Pinkava wrote the original concepts of
the film, although he was never formally named the director of the film.
In 2005, following Pinkava's departure from Pixar for lacking confidence in the story
development, Bird was approached to direct the film and revise the story.
Bird and some of the film's crew members also visited Paris for inspiration.
To create the food animation used in the film, the crew
consulted chefs from both France and the United States.
Lewis interned at Thomas Keller's The French Laundry restaurant, where
Keller developed the confit byaldi, a dish used in the film.
Michael Giacchino composed the Paris-inspired music for the film.
Ratatouille premiered on June 22, 2007, at the Kodak Theatre in Los Angeles,
California, with its general release on June 29, in the United States.
The film became a critical and commercial success,
grossing $623.7 million worldwide.
It finished its theatrical run as the sixth highest-grossing film of 2007 and the
year's second highest-grossing animated film (behind Shrek the Third).
The film received widespread acclaim for its screenplay,
animation, humor, voice acting, and Giacchino's score.
It also won the Academy Award for Best Animated Feature and was
nominated for several more, including Best Original Screenplay.
Ratatouille was later voted one of the hundred greatest motion pictures of the 21st
century by a 2016 poll of international critics conducted by the BBC.
The film explores themes of work, sibling relationship,
paris, france, expensive restaurant, river.
The tone is lighthearted.